Here, we have the dog object with a couple properties on it.
这是一个具有多个属性的 dog 对象
Three of which are actually methods.
其中三个实际上是方法
Let's check out each of these methods and see how each of them can
我们看看每个方法
access the dog object using the special "this" keyword.
以及每个方法可以如何使用特殊的“this”关键字访问 dog 对象
Let's start off the very top, "whatIsThis".
我们从最上面的 whatIsThis 开始
If we called "whatIsThis" on dog,
如果对 dog 调用 whatIsThis
all it's going to do is print out the value of "this" to the console.
它将向控制台中输出值“this”
So let's see what this looks like.
我们看看 this 是什么
Pretty interesting. So it looks like we have
很有趣 看起来像
an object with a couple of properties on it: name,
具有几个属性的对象
age, "whatIsThis", woof, and "ageOneYear".
name age whatIsThis woof 和 ageOneYear
It's actually the same set of properties as the properties in dog
它实际上和 dog 中的属性一样
because "this" refers to the dog object itself.
因为 this 指代 dog 对象本身
That's pretty straightforward. Check out the next one.
这很直白 看看下个方法
If we call the "woof" on dog,
如果对 dog 调用 woof
what we get printed to the console is the message, "Jodi says 'woof!'"
输出到控制台中的消息是“Jodi says 'woof!’”
So, let's kind of explore how it does that.
看看如何输出了这一消息
So when woof, what's your console logging is
调用 woof 时 控制台日志输出内容为
this.name concatenated with a string says "woof".
this.name 加上字符串“woof”
So, we know for the example that "this",
例如 我们知道 this
just refers to the dog object.
指代 dog 对象
So, this is dog,
这是 dog
accessing the name property gets us the string "Jodi".
访问 name 属性获得了字符串“Jodi”
So if you add that together this.name which is Jodi plus "says 'woof!'",
加起来的话 this.name 为 Jodi 再加上“says 'woof!'”
you get "Jodi says 'woof!'".
结果为“Jodi says 'woof!'”
Great. So we'll check out the next one, "ageOneYear".
我们看看下一个属性 ageOneYear
Let's go ahead and call this one on dog.
我们对 dog 调用此属性
It looks like what we get is current age: 8.
结果为“current age: 8”
So how does it do that?
如何获得这一结果的？
Let's take a look a little more closely at the "ageOneYear" method.
我们再仔细研究下 ageOneYear 方法
So, we see that it accesses the this.age property and increments that by a value of 1.
它访问了 this.age 属性并使其值加 1
Well, again we know "this" refers to a dog.
同样 我们知道 this 指代 dog
So if we grab the age property of dog,
如果获取 dog 的 age 属性
we can see that it's a value of 7.
可以看出它的值为 7
And then 7 incremented by 1,
然后使 7 加 1
is going to give you 8.
结果为 8
And after that, all the method does is
然后 该方法的作用是
that it's going to print the console the string "Current
向控制台中输出字符串“Current age”
age" and concatenate that with this.age which is now going to be 8.
并加上 this.age 后者现在为 8
So, "ageOneYear" can not only access the age property of the dog object,
因此 ageOneYear 不仅能访问 dog 对象的 age 属性
it can also directly mutate it by incrementing it by a value of 1.
还可以直接修改它 使其值加 1
So everything you just saw here was possible using
刚才的一切操作都可以通过关键字 this 实现
the "this" keyword which gives methods access to the object on which it was called.
关键字 this 使方法能够访问在其上调用它的对象